<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Saurabh Shah</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 12:39:07 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 12:39:07 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to crack GSOC?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; src=&quot;/images/GSOC/gsoc2016logo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Google Summer of Code&lt;/i&gt; is a global program that offers student developers stipends to write code for various open source software projects. It’s main aim is to introduce students to the world of open source programming. It is the best opportunity a student can get during his college career to work on real world software projects. I am currently a GSoC student in Ruby organization. In this post I will walk your way through, step by step, on how to crack Google Summer of Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Flip bits, not burgers!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bwake-up-earlyb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wake up early!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are really interested in GsoC, rise early. Make up your mind and kill your time surfing different open source organizations. If you have never contributed open source before then you are going to take an ample amount of time learning the way things work. Remember that its never too early to start preparing for GsoC. After all, GsoC is all about open source contributions which can be done at any stage of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;The distance is nothing; it&#39;s only the first step that is difficult.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bmake-new-friends--ubuntu-and-githubb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Make new friends : Ubuntu and Github&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a windows user I suggest switching to any of the flavours of ubuntu as quickly as possible. Start befriending your terminal and become familiar with the tools you use. Most of the software installations are pretty easy on ubuntu and many of them don’t even have windows support. Start using ubuntu on daily basis and you will love it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Avoid the Gates of Hell. Use ubuntu.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All organizations use some form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Getting-Started-About-Version-Control&quot;&gt;version control&lt;/a&gt; and most of them use git. Github makes it quick and easy for you to publish your work and collaborate on the work of other people. So if you are unfamiliar with words like version control, git, github then the first task is to master them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bfinding-organizationsb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Finding organizations&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started with GsoC, all I used to hear is first select one programming language of your choice and select an organization based on that. I completely disagree with this. I think you need to be versatile in selecting the organizations. So select a bag of languages, some of which you know and others you are interested in learning. For e.g I was interested in the field of big data analytics and data science. So I was ready to learn R, scala, python and upcoming language in this field like ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next task is to find all the organizations based on these languages. You can select them from the list of organizations that were selected previous year. Join the mailing lists of these organizations. Introduce yourself to the community and ask them on how to get started with their organization. Understand the technologies they use and proceed learning all you need to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgflip.com/i/16cwg8&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgflip.com/16cwg8.jpg&quot; title=&quot;made at imgflip.com&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t just rush your way through this process or get stuck in a single organization. You never know which organizations are getting selected the next year and which one’s won’t. Go through the selected list of organizations from previous years, 2015, 2014 to see if they got selected. The best of your chance is to remain in contact with as many organizations as you can at this point. Follow up on their reply and do as they ask. Sometimes, they give you small tasks to complete. Eliminate those organizations which are way too difficult to understand, one’s with no replies, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bcode-code-codeb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Code! Code! Code!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, your journey till now was just to get the feel of how open source community works. Real action must begin now. You should setup a development environment for the software/ application you are interested in. This is ugliest phase of all as most of the applications do not have a very well written installation script, however this is where perseverance comes into picture. If there comes up any issue just ask away on the IRC channel or the mailing list. Trust me, someone would always answer !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/GSOC/code.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;img align=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/GSOC/code.jpg&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot;&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’re done with all this, you should probably browse through their issue tracker (bugzilla, github or whatever they use) and look for a suitable bug. If you’re able to fix some bugs, you’re on the right track and doing great! However if you are not able to, try to go through the code again, and never ever stop trying. One of the many things that you would learn in GsoC is the ability of understanding complex piece of code in short period of time, and perseverance, two important abilities that are expected in a software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributions are considered most valuable in GsoC. May it be a small bug fix or a great patch, they will appreciate you. You will be known inside the community which will make your chances of selection better ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bproposal-makingb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Proposal making&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most important phase of your GsoC journey. Your proposal will be throughly evaluated by your mentors. Making a &lt;a href=&quot;http://teom.org/blog/kde/how-to-write-a-kick-ass-proposal-for-google-summer-of-code/&quot;&gt;kickass proposal&lt;/a&gt; is always considered more important than your past contributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you might have zeroed down to about two or three organizations in which you should be contributing. Go through their proposed list of projects. All this projects will seem intimidating for a start. So give enough time to understand the projects. Google your stuff. The earlier you start, the stronger your proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/GSOC/download.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is generally considered a bad idea to apply to just one organisation. Even if you are a very active contributor to a specific project and are assured of getting selected, consider applying to another project. Go through the same cycle as you did with the first project. It will be much easier to dive into this new organisation because you are already familiar with where to look and what to ask. It will be tiresome, and you’ll have to divide time, but it might be worth it.(Believe me!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bhappy-programmingb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Happy Programming&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all you can do to lift your chances in getting selected for GSOC. All the things I pointed out are not always the expected circumstances. Situations change. They change all the time. Act your way smart. Once you have taken the initiative never turn back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/GSOC/download (1).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/gsoc/2016/06/24/How-to-Crack-GSOC.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gsoc/2016/06/24/How-to-Crack-GSOC.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>GSOC</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to use Yummy Jekyll as your jekyll theme!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;yummy-jekyll&quot;&gt;Yummy Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-install&quot;&gt;How to install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;licence&quot;&gt;Licence&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 16:55:35 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/personal/2016/05/13/welcome-to-yummy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/personal/2016/05/13/welcome-to-yummy.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CSS Animation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick note about CSS animation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;css-animation&quot;&gt;CSS Animation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSS3 animation lets an element gradually change from one style to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;@keyframes&lt;/code&gt; to define an animation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set this animation on an element with animation properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could set properties one-by-one or with following shorthand:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;animation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;animation-name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;animation-duration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;animation-timing-function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;animation-delay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;animation-iteration-count&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;animation-direction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;animation-fill-mode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;animation-play-state&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;];&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keyframes&quot;&gt;@keyframes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It defines what the animation looks like at each stage of the animation timeline. It is composed of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Name of the animation. For example, changeColor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stages: From 0% to 100% to represent the whole process of animation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSS Properties: The CSS properties defined for each stage of the animation timeline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following example creates an animation called &lt;code&gt;changeColor&lt;/code&gt; and assign it to &lt;code&gt;div:hover&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;@keyframes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;changeColor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;60&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;green&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;:hover&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;animation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;changeColor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;5s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ease&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;.1s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In above example, we could also use &lt;code&gt;from&lt;/code&gt; to represent &lt;code&gt;0%&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;to&lt;/code&gt; to represent &lt;code&gt;100%&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;animation-properties&quot;&gt;Animation Properties&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has following properties:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;animation-name&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;animation-duration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;animation-timing-function&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;animation-delay&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;animation-iteration-count&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;animation-direction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;animation-fill-mode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;animation-play-state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animation-name&quot;&gt;animation-name&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name of the animation, defined in the @keyframes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animation-duration&quot;&gt;animation-duration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The duration of the animation, in seconds (e.g., 5s) or milliseconds (e.g., 200ms).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animation-timing-function&quot;&gt;animation-timing-function&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speed curve or pace of the animation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Timing Function&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;linear&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The animation has the same speed from start to end&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ease&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Default value&lt;/strong&gt;. The animation has a slow start, then fast, before it ends slowly.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ease-in&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Start slowly and end fast.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ease-out&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Start more quickly than linear ones and end slowly. The opposite of ease-in.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ease-in-out&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Both a slow start and a slow end&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;initial&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sets this property to its default value. So &lt;code&gt;ease&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;inherit&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Inherits this property from its parent element.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Check &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/fundamentals/design-and-ui/animations/the-basics-of-easing?hl=en&quot;&gt;The basics of easing&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animation-delay&quot;&gt;animation-delay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It specifies when the animation will start. The value is defined in seconds (s) or milliseconds (mil).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animation-iteration-count&quot;&gt;animation-iteration-count&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It specifies the number of times that the animation will play. The possible values are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a specific number of iterations (default is 1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;infinite&lt;/code&gt; - repeats forever&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;initial&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;inherit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animation-direction&quot;&gt;animation-direction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It specifies whether the animation should play forward, reverse, or in alternate cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;normal&lt;/code&gt; - Default. On each cycle the animation resets to the beginning state (0%) and plays forward again (to 100%).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;reverse&lt;/code&gt; - On each cycle the animation resets to the end state (100%) and plays backwards (to 0%).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;alternate&lt;/code&gt; - On each odd cycle, the animation plays forward (0% to 100%). On each even cycle, the animation plays backwards (100% to 0%).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;alternate-reverse&lt;/code&gt; - On each odd cycle, the animation plays in reverse (100% to 0%). On each even cycle, the animation plays forward (0% or 100%).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animation-fill-mode&quot;&gt;animation-fill-mode&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It specifies if the animation styles are visible before or after the animation plays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;normal&lt;/code&gt; - Default. The animation does not apply any styles to the element, before or after the animation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;forwards&lt;/code&gt; - After the animation is finished, the styles defined in the final keyframe (100%) are retained by the element.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;backwards&lt;/code&gt; - Before the animation (during the animation delay), the styles of the initial keyframe (0%) are applied to the element.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;both&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;code&gt;forwards&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;backwards&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animation-play-state&quot;&gt;animation-play-state&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two values: &lt;code&gt;running&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;paused&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It specifies whether the animation is &lt;code&gt;playing&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;paused&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Resuming a paused animation starts the animation where it was left off. But if pause an animation, the element style will return back to its origin.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;:hover&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;animation-play-state&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;paused&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;multiple-animations&quot;&gt;Multiple Animations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add multiple animations to a selector with comma:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;animation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;animationA&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;2s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;animationB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;2s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;refs&quot;&gt;Refs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imooc.com/learn/33&quot;&gt;Imooc 十天精通CSS3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://robots.thoughtbot.com/css-animation-for-beginners#animation-iteration-count&quot;&gt;CSS Animation for Beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3schools.com/cssref/css3_pr_animation-timing-function.asp&quot;&gt;CSS3 animation-timing-function Property&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/gsoc/2016/04/22/CSS-Animation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gsoc/2016/04/22/CSS-Animation.html</guid>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
        
        <category>GSoC</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Second Home</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-second-home&quot;&gt;My Second Home&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my Whatsapp status saying ‘Missing DA’ to the ones made from my Facebook post of ‘Missing DA’, one could easily infer that I was genuinely and sincerely ‘Missing DA’ all throughout this biting cold December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The immortalized memories of my time here full of nostalgia was what prompted me to write my first article for Entelechy, devoted to the wonderful time spent here in DA-IICT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the end of examinations in college, as I was preparing to go back home, and while I was packing my bags and putting everything in order; I thought of my ‘Home Sweet Home’, and I felt extremely excited by the thought of going back to my own house. Meeting my mother and father after quite a long time, eating delicious home-cooked food and meeting all of my old best friends from school – all of that lured me into that illusionary delight at the thought of getting to go back home finally. But that didn’t last very long.
After a few days, the changes in my perception of being away from college and feeling satiated at home were quite drastic. I was extremely happy to meet my mom and dad after such a long time, but as the days passed, I felt like something inside me was missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began to miss all of my dearest friends in DA-IICT, their idiotic jokes followed by the obvious consequent laughter, the Harlem Shake that we danced away to – which was quite a thrilling and bold experience, done on the day just before the infamous “Calculus Deal”, watching movies on some random senior’s laptop and lots of those fun-filled, completely chaotic things that we did. The food at home was wonderful, but it wasn’t the way Chotu bhai made it, in his obviated ‘Chotu Bhai’ style nor did I have any of my friends gathering around me in canteen as I shared my lunches and dinners and other meals with them, like a daily ritual that was subconsciously imbibed in me. As December mockingly dragged on, I grew extremely sick of my vacations and started missing all the cutthroat competition that happened in college right around the exam time. I began to realize that more than the pressure of exams, it was the group studies that took place then that I enjoyed the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;middle&quot; src=&quot;/images/daiict.jpg&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; width=&quot;800px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, one of my closest friend’s birthday was coming. From our conversations, I could make out that inspite of the fact that his Mom and Dad were there to celebrate his birthday and would ensure a wonderful celebration of the occasion; his birthday was still missing the spark of those ruthless hostel friends and the way they “celebrate” your birthday, branded slippers, selfie snaps, late night CR’s and of course our own exotic reinterpretation of the traditional “birthday party”. His 12 am counter-survivals to the birthday bashes were in-felicitously replaced by numerous midnight stroke-of-the-hour birthday calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And surely, how could I forget the most important events of first semester: Was it Concours? Or IFEST?
The answer to these questions is neither. The most important “events” as such for us in the first semester, were indeed the ‘HM Meeting’ events that were held throughout the semester. The randomness of twenty different people in one group gathering up time and again in the CEP, lab or cafe; the rampant fear of our survival on the day of the presentation in front of ‘Pandya Sir’ and the incessant reading of humanities literature leaving those supposedly tagged important courses behind; all of that complicated quite a huge chunk of our simple-headed lives. My initial discontentment about the course was undoubtedly removed as we progressed through it and reached the end and it will always remain the most extraordinarily interesting subject for me in my engineering studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best lesson that I learnt here is that the world doesn’t revolve around our CPI’s. College is all about the opportunities that you get and the experiences you gain, not the markings on your final transcript. Although the battle for pointers is ineludible, we do have quite a classic battle-field to rejoice about!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find myself the most fortunate as I am not among those fourth yearites who are trying to prepare themselves to slowly and subtly drift away from their humorous friends, affectionate lovers, hopped-up clubs, hostel life and most importantly losing all of that which constitutes their daily part of COLLEGE LIFE. The dreariness is spreading over the whole campus in view of their departure. As far as the students of the first year are concerned, I am glad that the journey is just a beginning, and we are geared up to drive ourselves farther ahead in the incredible expedition towards success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly, the most astonishing amongst all of the happenings of the previous year was getting admission in DA-IICT and enjoying living in the inferiority complex of it. I tried my best to intricate my feelings for DA-IICT but words will surely fail to elaborate my emotions, affection and sentiments associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/personal/2015/01/30/My-Second-Home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/personal/2015/01/30/My-Second-Home.html</guid>
        
        <category>College</category>
        
        <category>DA-IICT</category>
        
        <category>Memories</category>
        
        
        <category>Personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
