<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Saurabh Shah</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 13:26:55 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 13:26:55 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSOC Journey - Midterm</title>
        <description>&lt;s&gt;Yeah, 28th of June it is, Google will either make a decision to end my GSOC journey or pay me the biggest check of my life.&lt;/s&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google chose the latter one. I passed! 52 conversations, personal messages and tonnes of github discussions, this was brainstorming. So on this day I decided to jot down the bittersweet memories which has impacted my life greatly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bman-of-the-hourb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Man of the hour&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23rd April turned out to be the biggest day of my life. Getting selected for Google Summer of Code is the biggest victory ever achieved. This marked the end of continuous grapple and beginning of fresh journey. This day I realized that GSOC is not just an internship which provides a huge lot of money. It presents the opportunity to work with someone who is far more experienced and intelligent than me. I get the chance to work with  an exceptional organization and contribute a real world software. GSOC for me was full of sacrifices which turned glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bfirst-hurdleb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;First hurdle&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a long time contributer of open source world. I started contributing open source with the soul purpose of cracking GSOC. So getting selected in &lt;b&gt;Ruby&lt;/b&gt; organization was a serious challenge.
Let’s start by quoting my mentor’s first message :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;” Congrats on being accepted!
For a start, we should start thinking about how we would be able to quickly benchmark across multiple commits.
From my previous discussions with @sam, we want to build a docker image for each commit made to Ruby and tag it with the commit’s SHA1. So a few things to think about here:
How can we automate the building of those images?
How do we build each image fast? (One solution is to build each image using the previous image as the base so we don’t have to recompile every thing each time)
Are we able to store everything on Docker hub?
Once this is done, we can start thinking about how to make the magic for bisecting happen “&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agh! This was &lt;b&gt;scary&lt;/b&gt;. Never heard any of these stuff before. Anyways, a Gsocer has to master the art of reading other’s code. And that’s what I did this whole period. I learnt docker and slowly figured out what each of these words meant. Went through thousands of lines of code inspecting the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, starting around mid-days of community bonding period we worked around 20 days setting up the docker images for each commit in ruby. I kept on learning new features, clarifying my doubts along the way. But one day mentor messaged me :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; “ As of right now, I’ll like you to stop working on the Docker integration stuff because I feel that we might have assigned you a task that is too difficult for you to complete given your current level of experience. Instead we will like you to focus on … “ &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and assigned me a new task. I need to take that as a failure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bits-differentb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;It’s different!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributing open source for a short time and getting selected in Ruby which works on language itself was intimidating. During this time I observed many differences in the way other organizations operate and how I steered my journey. There are many organizations which have there prime focus on GSOC projects for development. In my case, its obvious that Ruby has many bigger activities to deal with. My mentor is mentoring two different GSOC organizations and is a core contributer of discourse along with rubybench. Again, its evident that he has greater problems to take care of. Besides, we don’t follow any specific timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blast-shotb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Last shot!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new task was :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;” What if all our benchmarks are implemented in Sequel? How fast would it be? How many objects would be allocated?
I feel we should split off all “database” specs from the Rails umbrella and make the suite of tests compare “sequel” to “Active Record”, as it stands it is totally unclear how much performance is left on the table cause there is nothing to compare “Active Record” to.
So start looking at our ActiveRecord benchmarks and write similar benchmarks using Sequel. “&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my last opportunity to prove myself before midterm. Till now, no real contributions(PR’s) on github. Fortunately this time, I had previous knowledge of activerecord. All I had to do was take my time to go through all the activerecord benchmarks and convert them to sequel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 days ago I got my greatest ever PR merged consisting of 593 additions and 29 deletions. This was exceptional and a huge relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgflip.com/i/16ix4v&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgflip.com/16ix4v.jpg&quot; title=&quot;made at imgflip.com&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Task remains to tackle frontend and my sequel benchmarks will be up and running in rubybench.org.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/gsoc/2016/06/27/GSOC-Journey-Midterm.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gsoc/2016/06/27/GSOC-Journey-Midterm.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>GSOC</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to crack GSOC?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; src=&quot;/images/GSOC/gsoc2016logo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Google Summer of Code&lt;/i&gt; is a global program that offers student developers stipends to write code for various open source software projects. It’s main aim is to introduce students to the world of open source programming. It is the best opportunity a student can get during his college career to work on real world software projects. I am currently a GSoC student in Ruby organization. In this post I will walk your way through, step by step, on how to crack Google Summer of Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Flip bits, not burgers!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bwake-up-earlyb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wake up early!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are really interested in GsoC, rise early. Make up your mind and kill your time surfing different open source organizations. If you have never contributed open source before then you are going to take an ample amount of time learning the way things work. Remember that its never too early to start preparing for GsoC. After all, GsoC is all about open source contributions which can be done at any stage of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;The distance is nothing; it&#39;s only the first step that is difficult.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bmake-new-friends--ubuntu-and-githubb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Make new friends : Ubuntu and Github&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a windows user I suggest switching to any of the flavours of ubuntu as quickly as possible. Start befriending your terminal and become familiar with the tools you use. Most of the software installations are pretty easy on ubuntu and many of them don’t even have windows support. Start using ubuntu on daily basis and you will love it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Avoid the Gates of Hell. Use ubuntu.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All organizations use some form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Getting-Started-About-Version-Control&quot;&gt;version control&lt;/a&gt; and most of them use git. Github makes it quick and easy for you to publish your work and collaborate on the work of other people. So if you are unfamiliar with words like version control, git, github then the first task is to master them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bfinding-organizationsb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Finding organizations&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started with GsoC, all I used to hear is first select one programming language of your choice and select an organization based on that. I completely disagree with this. I think you need to be versatile in selecting the organizations. So select a bag of languages, some of which you know and others you are interested in learning. For e.g I was interested in the field of big data analytics and data science. So I was ready to learn R, scala, python and upcoming language in this field like ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next task is to find all the organizations based on these languages. You can select them from the list of organizations that were selected previous year. Join the mailing lists of these organizations. Introduce yourself to the community and ask them on how to get started with their organization. Understand the technologies they use and proceed learning all you need to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgflip.com/i/16cwg8&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgflip.com/16cwg8.jpg&quot; title=&quot;made at imgflip.com&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t just rush your way through this process or get stuck in a single organization. You never know which organizations are getting selected the next year and which one’s won’t. Go through the selected list of organizations from previous years, 2015, 2014 to see if they got selected. The best of your chance is to remain in contact with as many organizations as you can at this point. Follow up on their reply and do as they ask. Sometimes, they give you small tasks to complete. Eliminate those organizations which are way too difficult to understand, one’s with no replies, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bcode-code-codeb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Code! Code! Code!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, your journey till now was just to get the feel of how open source community works. Real action must begin now. You should setup a development environment for the software/ application you are interested in. This is ugliest phase of all as most of the applications do not have a very well written installation script, however this is where perseverance comes into picture. If there comes up any issue just ask away on the IRC channel or the mailing list. Trust me, someone would always answer !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/GSOC/code.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;img align=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/GSOC/code.jpg&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot;&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’re done with all this, you should probably browse through their issue tracker (bugzilla, github or whatever they use) and look for a suitable bug. If you’re able to fix some bugs, you’re on the right track and doing great! However if you are not able to, try to go through the code again, and never ever stop trying. One of the many things that you would learn in GsoC is the ability of understanding complex piece of code in short period of time, and perseverance, two important abilities that are expected in a software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributions are considered most valuable in GsoC. May it be a small bug fix or a great patch, they will appreciate you. You will be known inside the community which will make your chances of selection better ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bproposal-makingb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Proposal making&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most important phase of your GsoC journey. Your proposal will be throughly evaluated by your mentors. Making a &lt;a href=&quot;http://teom.org/blog/kde/how-to-write-a-kick-ass-proposal-for-google-summer-of-code/&quot;&gt;kickass proposal&lt;/a&gt; is always considered more important than your past contributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you might have zeroed down to about two or three organizations in which you should be contributing. Go through their proposed list of projects. All this projects will seem intimidating for a start. So give enough time to understand the projects. Google your stuff. The earlier you start, the stronger your proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/GSOC/download.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is generally considered a bad idea to apply to just one organisation. Even if you are a very active contributor to a specific project and are assured of getting selected, consider applying to another project. Go through the same cycle as you did with the first project. It will be much easier to dive into this new organisation because you are already familiar with where to look and what to ask. It will be tiresome, and you’ll have to divide time, but it might be worth it.(Believe me!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bhappy-programmingb&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Happy Programming&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all you can do to lift your chances in getting selected for GSOC. All the things I pointed out are not always the expected circumstances. Situations change. They change all the time. Act your way smart. Once you have taken the initiative never turn back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/GSOC/download (1).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/gsoc/2016/06/24/How-to-Crack-GSOC.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gsoc/2016/06/24/How-to-Crack-GSOC.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>GSOC</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Second Home</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-second-home&quot;&gt;My Second Home&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my Whatsapp status saying ‘Missing DA’ to the ones made from my Facebook post of ‘Missing DA’, one could easily infer that I was genuinely and sincerely ‘Missing DA’ all throughout this biting cold December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The immortalized memories of my time here full of nostalgia was what prompted me to write my first article for Entelechy, devoted to the wonderful time spent here in DA-IICT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the end of examinations in college, as I was preparing to go back home, and while I was packing my bags and putting everything in order; I thought of my ‘Home Sweet Home’, and I felt extremely excited by the thought of going back to my own house. Meeting my mother and father after quite a long time, eating delicious home-cooked food and meeting all of my old best friends from school – all of that lured me into that illusionary delight at the thought of getting to go back home finally. But that didn’t last very long.
After a few days, the changes in my perception of being away from college and feeling satiated at home were quite drastic. I was extremely happy to meet my mom and dad after such a long time, but as the days passed, I felt like something inside me was missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began to miss all of my dearest friends in DA-IICT, their idiotic jokes followed by the obvious consequent laughter, the Harlem Shake that we danced away to – which was quite a thrilling and bold experience, done on the day just before the infamous “Calculus Deal”, watching movies on some random senior’s laptop and lots of those fun-filled, completely chaotic things that we did. The food at home was wonderful, but it wasn’t the way Chotu bhai made it, in his obviated ‘Chotu Bhai’ style nor did I have any of my friends gathering around me in canteen as I shared my lunches and dinners and other meals with them, like a daily ritual that was subconsciously imbibed in me. As December mockingly dragged on, I grew extremely sick of my vacations and started missing all the cutthroat competition that happened in college right around the exam time. I began to realize that more than the pressure of exams, it was the group studies that took place then that I enjoyed the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;middle&quot; src=&quot;/images/daiict.jpg&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; width=&quot;800px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, one of my closest friend’s birthday was coming. From our conversations, I could make out that inspite of the fact that his Mom and Dad were there to celebrate his birthday and would ensure a wonderful celebration of the occasion; his birthday was still missing the spark of those ruthless hostel friends and the way they “celebrate” your birthday, branded slippers, selfie snaps, late night CR’s and of course our own exotic reinterpretation of the traditional “birthday party”. His 12 am counter-survivals to the birthday bashes were in-felicitously replaced by numerous midnight stroke-of-the-hour birthday calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And surely, how could I forget the most important events of first semester: Was it Concours? Or IFEST?
The answer to these questions is neither. The most important “events” as such for us in the first semester, were indeed the ‘HM Meeting’ events that were held throughout the semester. The randomness of twenty different people in one group gathering up time and again in the CEP, lab or cafe; the rampant fear of our survival on the day of the presentation in front of ‘Pandya Sir’ and the incessant reading of humanities literature leaving those supposedly tagged important courses behind; all of that complicated quite a huge chunk of our simple-headed lives. My initial discontentment about the course was undoubtedly removed as we progressed through it and reached the end and it will always remain the most extraordinarily interesting subject for me in my engineering studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best lesson that I learnt here is that the world doesn’t revolve around our CPI’s. College is all about the opportunities that you get and the experiences you gain, not the markings on your final transcript. Although the battle for pointers is ineludible, we do have quite a classic battle-field to rejoice about!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find myself the most fortunate as I am not among those fourth yearites who are trying to prepare themselves to slowly and subtly drift away from their humorous friends, affectionate lovers, hopped-up clubs, hostel life and most importantly losing all of that which constitutes their daily part of COLLEGE LIFE. The dreariness is spreading over the whole campus in view of their departure. As far as the students of the first year are concerned, I am glad that the journey is just a beginning, and we are geared up to drive ourselves farther ahead in the incredible expedition towards success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly, the most astonishing amongst all of the happenings of the previous year was getting admission in DA-IICT and enjoying living in the inferiority complex of it. I tried my best to intricate my feelings for DA-IICT but words will surely fail to elaborate my emotions, affection and sentiments associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/personal/2015/01/30/My-Second-Home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/personal/2015/01/30/My-Second-Home.html</guid>
        
        <category>College</category>
        
        <category>DA-IICT</category>
        
        <category>Memories</category>
        
        
        <category>Personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
